<resources>
    <string name="app_name">History Quiz</string>

    <string name="q1">Which of these works takes place during the Hmelnitsky uprising in Ukraine?</string>
    <string name="q1a">Ivan Franko, “Turbulent Times”</string>
    <string name="q1b">Nikolai Gogol, “Taras Bulba”</string>
    <string name="q1c">Mikhail Lermontov, “A Hero of Our Time”</string>
    <string name="q1d">Henryk Sienkiewicz, “With Fire and Sword”</string>
    <string name="q1e">Johannes Vastovius , “The Vine of the North”</string>
    <string name="q1Answer">1. Taras Bulba and With Fire and Sword are about the Hmelnitsky uprising.</string>

    <string name="q2">What is the purpose of a Cossack’s forelock hairstyle?</string>
    <string name="q2a">It brushes the devil off his shoulder</string>
    <string name="q2b">It gives St. Peter something to hold on to so he can pull the Cossack out of the pits of hell into heaven</string>
    <string name="q2c">It honours a legendary warrior saint</string>
    <string name="q2d">It makes it easier to tell apart Tatars, Cossacks, and Polish at a greater distance</string>
    <string name="q2Answer">2. A Cossack’s forelock brushes the devil off his shoulder, and helps St. Peter pull him out of hell.</string>

    <string name="q3">Which pair of countries below has fought the most wars with each other?</string>
    <string name="q3a">Poland and Russia</string>
    <string name="q3b">Prussia and Poland</string>
    <string name="q3c">Spain and Holland</string>
    <string name="q3d">Hungary and the Ottoman Empire</string>
    <string name="q3e">Denmark and Sweden</string>
    <string name="q3Answer">3. Denmark and Sweden has fought the most wars with each other. By some reckonings, this pair has fought more wars than any other pair of countries in the world.</string>

    <string name="q4">Alexander Nevsky became a hero of Russia by battling:</string>
    <string name="q4a">Swedes</string>
    <string name="q4b">The Knights of the Sword</string>
    <string name="q4c">Poland-Lithuania</string>
    <string name="q4d">The Teutonic Knights</string>
    <string name="q4e">The Golden Horde</string>
    <string name="q4Answer">4. Alexander Nevsky became a hero due to the Battle of the Ice against the Teutonic Knights. There is little real evidence of Nevsky battling Swedes, and he dealt with the Golden Horde through diplomacy.</string>

    <string name="q5">Peter the Great tried to modernise Russia by, among other things, taxing the nobility’s:</string>
    <string name="q5a">Vodka</string>
    <string name="q5b">Carriages</string>
    <string name="q5c">Hunting rifles</string>
    <string name="q5d">Beards</string>
    <string name="q5e">Horses</string>
    <string name="q5Answer">5. Peter the Great taxed the beards of the nobles. The intended effect was to make the noble boyars adopt modern fashions, and by extension, modern attitudes.</string>

    <string name="q6">Hussars are originally from:</string>
    <string name="q6a">Hungary</string>
    <string name="q6b">Poland</string>
    <string name="q6c">Lithuania</string>
    <string name="q6d">Ukraine</string>
    <string name="q6e">France</string>
    <string name="q6Answer">6. Hussars are originally from Hungary.</string>

    <string name="q7">Cossack traditional clothing inspired the national dress of which of these countries?</string>
    <string name="q7a">Lithuania</string>
    <string name="q7b">Ukraine</string>
    <string name="q7c">Georgia</string>
    <string name="q7d">Uzbekistan</string>
    <string name="q7e">Azerbaijan</string>
    <string name="q7Answer">7. Cossacks influenced national dress in Ukraine, Georgia, and Azerbaijan - in the latter cases, through the Don Cossack coats known as cherkassky.</string>

    <string name="q8">The Swedish king Gustav Adolf commissioned the great battleship “Wasa” for his war against Poland-Lithuania, which sank on its maiden voyage inside the Stockholm Archipelago.  The ship has since been recovered and is housed in a museum in Stockholm.  In what year did the Wasa sink?</string>
    <string name="q8a">Year</string>
    <string name="q8Answer">8. The Wasa sank in 1628.</string>

    <string name="q9">Which Cossack leader is immortalised in the song “Volga, my motherland”?</string>
    <string name="q9a">Yemelyan Pugachev</string>
    <string name="q9b">Ivan Bohun</string>
    <string name="q9c">Stepan Razin</string>
    <string name="q9d">Ivan Mazepa</string>
    <string name="q9e">Bogdan Hmelnitsky</string>
    <string name="q9Answer">9. “Volga, my motherland” is about Stepan Razin - the alternate title of the song is “Stenka Razin”.</string>

    <string name="q10">The region Courland was previously a Duchy, controlled at various times by Livonia, Sweden, Poland-Lithuania, Russia, and others. In which country is Courland located today?</string>
    <string name="q10a">Estonia</string>
    <string name="q10b">Latvia</string>
    <string name="q10c">Lithuania</string>
    <string name="q10d">Poland</string>
    <string name="q10e">Finland</string>
    <string name="q10Answer">Courland is now Western Latvia.</string>

    <string name="answerButton">Check my answer</string>

    <string name="toast1">You got </string>
    <string name="toast2"> out of 10 questions correct!</string>

    <string name="awesome">Excellent work!</string>
    <string name="good">These questions are hard, so well done!</string>
    <string name="low">If you enjoy learning about Eastern Europe, maybe check out some more books or films about this subject?</string>

</resources>
